<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!-- The below text should read "UNICODE UTF-8" -->
<!-- If it does not, please make sure that you are using a Unicode UTF-8 compatible editor -->
<!-- ＵＮＩＣＯＤＥ ＵＴＦ-８ -->
<lesson>
	<!-- Please do not change the below line -->
	<copyright>Copyright © 2001-2005, Ricci Adams</copyright>

	<!-- Change the below text to read "Translation by Your Name" -->
	<!-- Example: -->
	<!--   <translation>Übersetzung von Ricci Adams</translation> -->
	<translation>Localisation by Max Perryment</translation>

	<!-- Translate all text between <var> and </var> -->
	<!-- Please do not alter the "name" values -->
	<var name="nullText">-</var>
	<var name="majorSeventhText">M7</var>
	<var name="minorSeventhText">m7</var>
	<var name="dominantSeventhText">D7</var>
	<var name="fullyDiminishedSeventhText">fd7</var>
	<var name="halfDiminishedSeventhText">hd7</var>
	
	<!-- Translate all text between <title> and </title> -->		
	<title>Diatonic Seventh Chords</title>

	<!-- Translate all text between <text> and </text> -->
	<!-- Please do not alter the <gotoAndStop>, <gotoAndPlay>, or <section> lines -->
	<section>
		<gotoAndStop label="start" />
		<text>In addition to diatonic triads, every major and minor scale has seven <b>diatonic seventh chords</b>.</text>
		<text>In the next example, we will find the diatonic seventh chords of the C Major Scale.</text>
		<gotoAndPlay label="major" />
		<text>First, start with the diatonic triads.</text>
		<gotoAndPlay label="major2" />
		<text>Next, stack a generic third on top of each triad.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major3" />
		<text>Finally, analyze the resulting seventh chords.</text>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_i" />
		<text>The first chord is a major triad and a major seventh.  Therefore, it is a major seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_ii" />
		<text>The second chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_iii" />
		<text>The third chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is also a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_iv" />
		<text>The fourth chord is a major triad and a major seventh.  Therefore, it is a major seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_v" />
		<text>The fifth chord is a major triad and a minor seventh.  This combination makes it a dominant seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_vi" />
		<text>The sixth chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_vii" />
		<text>Chord number seven is a diminished triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a half-diminished seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="major_viii" />
		<text>Finally, the last chord is the same as the first.</text>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<gotoAndPlay label="minor" />
		<text>Next, we will analyze the diatonic seventh chords of the C natural minor scale.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_i" />
		<text>The first chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_ii" />
		<text>The second chord is a diminished triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a half-diminished seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_iii" />
		<text>The third chord is a major triad and a major seventh.  Therefore, it is a major seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_iv" />
		<text>The fourth chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_v" />
		<text>The fifth chord is a minor triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is also a minor seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_vi" />
		<text>The sixth chord is a major triad and a major seventh.  Therefore, it is a major seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_vii" />
		<text>Chord number seven is a major triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a dominant seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="minor_viii" />
		<text>Again, the last chord is the same as the first.</text>
	</section>

	<section>
		<gotoAndPlay label="harmonic" />
		<text>Finally, we will analyze the diatonic seventh chords of the C harmonic minor scale.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="harmonic_i" />
		<text>Since the first chord contains a minor triad and major seventh, it doesn't fit any of the seventh chords that we have learned.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="harmonic_iii" />
		<text>Since the third chord contains an augmented triad, it also doesn't fit.  These two chords are rarely used.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="harmonic_v" />
		<text>The fifth chord now contains a major triad and a minor seventh.  Therefore, it is a dominant seventh chord.</text>
		<gotoAndStop label="harmonic_vii" />
		<text>Finally, chord number seven contains a diminished triad and a diminished seventh.  Therefore, it is a diminished seventh chord.</text>
	</section>

	<section>
		<gotoAndStop label="analysis" />
		<text>We will now discuss the analysis symbols for diatonic seventh chords.</text>
		<gotoAndPlay label="analysis2" />
		<text>Recall the symbols for the harmonic minor diatonic triads.</text>
		<gotoAndPlay label="analysis3" />
		<text>We simply add a small seven to the top right corner of each roman numeral.</text>
		<gotoAndPlay label="analysis4" />
		<text>If the seventh chord is half diminished, a slash is placed through the circle.</text>
	</section>

</lesson>